Sometimes it says Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī worships Sūrya.
A volte, si dice, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī adora Sūrya.
[Ultimate Nectar Extraction]
[La Suprema Estrazione DI Nettare]
The famous yoga mantras mention, Guru Mahārāj said, Nārāyaṇ.
I famosi mantra di yoga menzionano, diceva Guru Mahārāj, Nārāyaṇ.
He quoted, and I don't have it committed to memory,
Egli citava - io non l'ho imparato a memoria -:
He's the light of the light.
«Egli è la luce della luce».
When you look at the sun, it's divine illumination, actually—we know that.
Quando guardi il sole, è una luce divina in realtà, lo sappiamo.
It's divine. Sun-light is divine. It's obvious.
È divino, la luce del sole è divina, è ovvio.
Every morning it's divine light.
Ogni mattina c'è una luce divina.
Nārāyaṇ is in the centre of the sun; the light of the light.
Nārāyaṇ è nel centro del sole: la luce della luce.
That's how Guru Mahārāj described.
Così Guru Mahārāj lo descriveva;
So if we're fortunate to give some appreciation and go deeper …
Allora, se siamo così fortunati da apprezzarlo e andare più a fondo...
Sometimes Guru Mahārāj ...
A volte Guru Mahārāj,
Śri Puram means the city of Her … that She's illuminating.
Śri Puram significa la città di Lei, che Lei sta illuminando.
The heart of Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī is illuminating the whole spiritual existence,
Il cuore di Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī illumina l'intera esistenza spirituale,
and revealing Kṛṣṇa.
e rivela Kṛṣṇa.
By the light of the sun we can see the Ghanaśyām; Śyāmasundar.
Grazie alla luce del sole, possiamo vedere il Ghanaśyām, Śyāmasundar.
Like this afternoon's clouds here are Ghanaśyām-like clouds, revealed by sunlight.
Come le nuvole di questo pomeriggio sono nuvole simili a Ghanaśyām, rivelate dalla luce del sole.
There, Kṛṣṇa's steps are very soft and short. He's a cowherd boy.
Lì, i passi di Kṛṣṇa sono molto delicati e brevi, lui è un pastorello.
Adbhuta-kram: 'He of wonderful stride and wonderful step.'
Adbhuta-kram: "Colui dalla meravigliosa andatura e dal meraviglioso passo".
Divine movement.
Movimento divino.
Movement enhanced with beauty is dance.
Il movimento arricchito dalla bellezza è danza.
The Kṛṣṇa movement is movement enhanced with beauty; dance.
Il movimento di Kṛṣṇa è un movimento arricchito di bellezza: danza.
The Kṛṣṇa movement is the most beautiful movement,
Il movimento di Kṛṣṇa è il movimento più bello,
other than 'that Kṛṣṇa'.
diverso da "quel Kṛṣṇa".
Gāndharvikā—Gāndharvā Govindasundar— Srila Guru Mahārāj's deity, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī,
Gāndharvikā—Gāndharvā Govindasundar, la divinità di Srila Guru Mahārāj, Śrīmatī Rādhārāṇī,
she's dancing and singing, attracting the centre of all attraction; Kṛṣṇa.
lei danza e canta, attraendo il centro di tutta l'attrazione: Kṛṣṇa.
Kṛṣ-ṇa.
Kṛṣ-ṇa,
'Attracting', kṛṣir bhū-vācakaḥ śabdo (Cc: 2.9.30).
"attraente", kṛṣir bhū-vācakaḥ śabdo (Cc: 2.9.30).
Kṛṣṇa, 'attracting everyone to the centre,
Kṛṣṇa attrae tutto verso il centro,
with His irresistible charm, beauty and sweetness';
con il Suo irresistibele fascino, bellezza e dolcezza.
Kṛṣ-ṇa, 'and then nourishing everyone'.
Kṛṣ-ṇa, e poi nutre tutti.
Hlādinī-śakti puṣṭi karan: Rādhārāṇī, extracting …
Hlādinī-śakti puṣṭi karan: Rādhārāṇī, estraendo...
It's great that Kṛṣṇa is Akhila-rasāmṛta-mūrti;
È gran cosa che Kṛṣṇa sia Akhila-rasāmṛta-mūrti.
He's ecstasy personified.
Egli è l'estasi personificata.
But who can extract the nectar?
Ma chi può estrarre il nettare?
... need nectar extraction.
C'è bisogno di estrarre il nettare.
So many things are like that, they have some ...
Allora, molte cose sono così. hanno qualche...
there's a method for how to extract.
c'è un metodo per estrarre,
The method to extract the nectar of Kṛṣṇa is sevā, self-giving, self-offering.
il metodo per estrarre il nettare di Kṛṣṇa è il sevā, il donarsi, l'offrisi.